<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Google on Luca Bruno blog</title>
    <link>https://lucabrun.github.io/tags/google/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google on Luca Bruno blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:54:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lucabrun.github.io/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Found my google reader alternative: the old reader</title>
      <link>https://lucabrun.github.io/2013/07/found-my-google-reader-alternative.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:54:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lucabrun.github.io/2013/07/found-my-google-reader-alternative.html</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;d like to share with you my google reader alternative: theoldreader.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried so far yoleo, feedly, goread and diggreader. Each of them is missing the following must have things for me:&#xA;The &amp;ldquo;next&amp;rdquo; button. I don&amp;rsquo;t like using keyboard bindings when reading feeds. Search through all feeds Social by sharing/liking news Exporting OPML Additionally, theoldreader has a great (disabled by default) feature: clicking on a news will scroll to it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DuckDuckGo search engine</title>
      <link>https://lucabrun.github.io/2010/09/duckduckgo-search-engine.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2010 05:16:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lucabrun.github.io/2010/09/duckduckgo-search-engine.html</guid>
      <description>Hello,&#xA;in this post I&amp;rsquo;d like to hint you a very nice search engine: DuckDuckGo. I&amp;rsquo;ve been pointed out to this by a post here on why both Google and Yahoo suck (and why Google search does more).&#xA;In older posts of mine you can find some examples on how Google search can miserably fail a search.&#xA;The main problem with the two approaches is: Google (and Bing too) sorts by popularity, Yahoo by match.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Reader Fail</title>
      <link>https://lucabrun.github.io/2010/05/google-reader-fail.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2010 12:08:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lucabrun.github.io/2010/05/google-reader-fail.html</guid>
      <description>Hello,&#xA;Google Reader has just wiped out my subscriptions list, which made me scream like a crazy monkey (other than cleaning up the list).Now I&amp;rsquo;m using bloglines, which looks pretty good except there&amp;rsquo;s nothing like &amp;ldquo;read all items&amp;rdquo;, but you must clean on each feed to see the items (any alternative to bloglines supporting this?).&#xA;But as far as I can see, I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one that lost the feeds, the difference is that I just opened the reader without any other operation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google search wrong again</title>
      <link>https://lucabrun.github.io/2010/03/google-search-wrong-again.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 04:37:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lucabrun.github.io/2010/03/google-search-wrong-again.html</guid>
      <description>Hello,&#xA;sometimes ago I posted twice about google search having wrong results.&#xA;Now it happens again after a few months (it&amp;rsquo;s like google breaks page weights like every 4-5 months).&#xA;The search is &amp;ldquo;debian dpkg list&amp;rdquo;, I really expect the mailing list info page but after 3-4 pages of google search (and also bing this time) I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find it. With yahoo search it&amp;rsquo;s at the first position (lists.debian.org/debian-dpkg).&#xA;Like for the previous posts, using different search engines matters and matches your needs.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
